<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="atom.xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://hushline.app/library/blog</id>
    <title>Hush Line Library Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://hushline.app/library/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Hush Line Library Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://hushline.app/library/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build One of The Highest Security Laptops for Under $200 with Qubes OS]]></title>
        <id>https://hushline.app/library/blog/build-a-qubes-laptop-for-under-two-hundred-dollars</id>
        <link href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/build-a-qubes-laptop-for-under-two-hundred-dollars"/>
        <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Qubes OS Cover]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Qubes OS Cover" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/cover-d210474abd20ba0691c4b4b6ddad1f70.png" width="1936" height="1119" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Qubes OS is widely regarded as one of the most secure operating systems available. Its strength comes from virtualization: instead of one system running everything, Qubes divides your tasks into isolated virtual machines.</p>
<p>Consider how this concept applies to your daily life. You may have a work laptop, a personal computer, and a school-issued Chromebook. Each device is kept separate for a reason—you don't want to job hunt on your work computer, or risk school monitoring on your personal device. In some cases, people handling sensitive information even keep an "air-gapped" machine that never connects to the internet, used only for opening files that pose a risk.</p>
<p>Qubes consolidates all of this into a single system. Work, personal, school, or air-gapped-style machines become separate virtual workstations, compartmentalized through their Xen-based architecture. These can run different operating systems, such as Fedora, Debian, Whonix for Tor, or even Windows, all at the same time.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="lets-begin">Let's Begin<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/build-a-qubes-laptop-for-under-two-hundred-dollars#lets-begin" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Let's Begin" title="Direct link to Let's Begin">​</a></h2>
<p>For this guide, we’ll use a <a href="https://a.co/d/6qDgkOi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dell Latitude 7280</a>, a fully supported laptop on the <a href="https://www.qubes-os.org/hcl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Qubes hardware compatibility list</a> and <a href="https://a.co/d/6qDgkOi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">available for under $200</a> (at the time of this writing) and convert it into a hardened, compartmentalized laptop.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Qubes OS Hardware Compatability List" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/hardware-03d59d21b1485353e445e1b17da4ea1a.png" width="1243" height="943" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>First, <a href="https://www.qubes-os.org/downloads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">go to the QubesOS site and download the latest stable ISO</a> of the operating system. It’s a little more than seven gigabytes, so it may take a few minutes.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Qubes OS Download Page" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/qubes-acc6d230fca578a2f09674e2e3005823.png" width="1092" height="865" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Once finished, <a href="https://etcher.balena.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">download and open BalenaEtcher</a>, an application that allows you to write your .iso file to a USB drive.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="BalenaEtcher installer" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/etcher-3a30ab7fe5dae61996f860c211a5306a.png" width="1000" height="680" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Once you finish flashing the drive, boot up the laptop where you'll install Qubes. For the Dell Latitude 7280, when the machine starts, press the F2 key rapidly to enter BIOS setup.</p>
<p>In Settings, navigate to&nbsp;<code>General &gt; Boot Sequence</code>. You'll see a list of drives for the laptop to prioritize; since we're installing Qubes from a USB drive, move <code>USB Storage Device</code> to the top. Apply the settings, plug the USB drive into the computer, then click Exit. Your laptop will reboot and use the USB drive containing the Qubes installer.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="BIOS Settings" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/bios-4b3b014132819515ea479265422b1dc0.png" width="3003" height="1684" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>After rebooting, you'll see the Qubes installation options. It'll automatically select&nbsp;<code>Test media and install Qubes OS [Rx.x.x]</code>, but you can press <code>ENTER</code> to select it manually.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Initial Qubes installer" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/installer-32c32577632f32274e2e14faa37e1ac2.png" width="3023" height="1696" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>When the installer begins, you'll choose your language. Next, click <code>Installation Destination</code>. Review the information and click <code>Done</code> in the top left corner to create the disk encryption password. Ensure you use a password manager and create a strong, random password or passphrase. In the next dialog titled <strong>Installation Options</strong>, click <code>Reclaim Space</code> to free up the necessary space for installation.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Install Destination" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/dest-c212698dd13fe5fc43302fe2644f5576.png" width="3002" height="1673" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>In the following dialog, click&nbsp;<code>Delete all</code>, then the <code>Reclaim space</code> button in the bottom right of the window.</p>
<p>Next, create a user. Use a different, strong password from your Disk Password. Finally, click&nbsp;<code>Begin Installation</code>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Initial Qubes installer 2" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/begin_install-9563995d9a0f5684fe58e3aa44d746cc.png" width="2997" height="1676" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="finishing-up">Finishing Up<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/build-a-qubes-laptop-for-under-two-hundred-dollars#finishing-up" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Finishing Up" title="Direct link to Finishing Up">​</a></h2>
<p>The initial installation process typically takes around 15 to 20 minutes. When complete, click&nbsp;<code>Reboot System</code>&nbsp;and remove the USB drive.</p>
<p>After rebooting, you'll be prompted to enter your disk password. Next, you'll see another installer screen. This time, click&nbsp;<code>QubesOS</code>&nbsp;on the first screen. The next screen gives options for configuring Qubes. The most important option here is&nbsp;to check <code>Enable system and template updates over the Tor anonymity network using Whonix</code>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Qubes configuration" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/config-abeb69a3c1f6e547a1e0df8431d85261.png" width="3012" height="1689" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>This next installation can take 45 minutes to an hour. When complete, you'll log in with the user you created in the first half of the process.</p>
<p>🎉 Congratulations, you now have one of the most secure computers in the world, for about the cost of a trip to the grocery store.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Glenn Sorrentino</name>
            <uri>https://scidsg.org</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="qubes" term="qubes"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Blow The Whistle Without Losing Your Career]]></title>
        <id>https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-blow-the-whistle-without-losing-your-career</id>
        <link href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-blow-the-whistle-without-losing-your-career"/>
        <updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No diving in the pool]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="No diving in the pool" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/cover-0a791e2c9c7080943782ad85040a8902.png" width="3072" height="1800" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I've talked to many, many whistleblowers over the years, and the story typically goes like this: see something, say something, become the problem, lose your job, face legal and financial issues, struggle to find another job. It's the paradox of whistleblowing; we valorize doing the right thing, and then attack the people who speak up. So here's another way to blow the whistle without risking everything.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="know-your-values">Know Your Values<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-blow-the-whistle-without-losing-your-career#know-your-values" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Know Your Values" title="Direct link to Know Your Values">​</a></h2>
<p>It's important to remember that in the hodgepodge of the office culture, there's a diversity of every kind of belief system. You aren't going to be in line politically with everyone, and that can't be a blocker for your performance. While on one hand, you must place your personal beliefs aside in some cases, in others, such as those involving legal or ethical disagreements, it's important to know where your line is.</p>
<p>A recent example that comes to mind is of an executive who became aware of extensive fraud within his company. Being in a leadership position, he wanted to fix the issue, but found that he was the only one willing to even talk about it. Things got uncomfortable, and realizing he couldn't make the progress he wanted, he resigned. Once the legal barrier was breached, he valued his freedom over loyalty to a company that could lead to prison.</p>
<p><em>Takeaway: It's better to leave a bad job.</em></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="keep-it-to-yourself">Keep It To Yourself<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-blow-the-whistle-without-losing-your-career#keep-it-to-yourself" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Keep It To Yourself" title="Direct link to Keep It To Yourself">​</a></h2>
<p>We're social animals after all, so this may go against your best instincts, but if you're concerned about significant legal or ethical violations, you shouldn't confide in anyone but a lawyer with privileged conversations. Gossip is the most efficient force in an office, so if you don't want people labeling you as a risk (even the ones you're aligned with), you need to keep it to yourself.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Loose lips" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/loose-lips-130e4d12082166f26ce8dba62e73b094.jpg" width="1280" height="1667" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><em>Takeaway: Loose lips sink ships.</em></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-about-internal-legal-and-hr">What About Internal Legal and HR?<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-blow-the-whistle-without-losing-your-career#what-about-internal-legal-and-hr" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What About Internal Legal and HR?" title="Direct link to What About Internal Legal and HR?">​</a></h2>
<p>An early lesson that everyone should learn before entering the job market is that your employer's legal and HR work for the company, not the employees. These offices are there to identify risks to the business and to eliminate liabilities. There's not much more to it than that. So even if you just got a new General Counsel or "Chief People Officer" who is young, hip, and garners trust, you are not their client or priority, no matter what they tell you.</p>
<p><em>Takeaway: HR is not your friend.</em></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="its-easy-to-get-caught">It's Easy To Get Caught<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-blow-the-whistle-without-losing-your-career#its-easy-to-get-caught" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to It's Easy To Get Caught" title="Direct link to It's Easy To Get Caught">​</a></h2>
<p>Are you reading this article as a concerned employee interested in blowing the whistle, and you're on your work computer? You've already misstepped. Workplace networks are almost always monitored, and the level of visibility is down to not only the website you visit, but also the web services that site uses. So if you visit nytimes.com, your employer will see that, as well as Google Analytics, or any other service the Times uses for their site. And for good reason; if you ever visit a seemingly benign site that uses a CDN in a "high-risk" country, you may be putting that network at risk.</p>
<p>Below is an exmaple of basic DNS monitoring. You can see different devices automatically making network calls, with full transparency about their activity.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Network Logs" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/logs-ee43f8e09aecf54579382e2aa6fc3ca0.gif" width="960" height="767" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><em>Takeaway: Never use a work computer, VPN, or network to do anything whistleblowing-related.</em></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="document-everything-but-dont-take-documents">Document Everything, But Don't Take Documents<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-blow-the-whistle-without-losing-your-career#document-everything-but-dont-take-documents" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Document Everything, But Don't Take Documents" title="Direct link to Document Everything, But Don't Take Documents">​</a></h2>
<p>A key piece of information you'll need to support your concerns is your own documentation. Were you in a meeting where you were asked to do something you and the room knew to be illegal? Take note of the date and time of what you were asked to do, and who was present. Use a personal, non-work-issued phone with disk-encryption enabled (iPhone does this by default) and a strong passcode to keep notes. If you use an iPhone, make sure Advanced Data Protection is enabled so your notes and backups are end-to-end encrypted.</p>
<p>While it may be tempting to use your phone's camera to take photos of your work computer, you should avoid this, since that can still be considered stealing company information. In fact, DO NOT take any documents from your workplace. You don't want to break the law trying to do the right thing. Wait until speaking to a lawyer before taking anything, including forwarding emails.</p>
<p><em>Takeaway: Taking documents, including photos of documents, can land you in jail.</em></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="talk-to-a-lawyer">Talk To a Lawyer<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-blow-the-whistle-without-losing-your-career#talk-to-a-lawyer" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Talk To a Lawyer" title="Direct link to Talk To a Lawyer">​</a></h2>
<p>You don't need a year's worth of notes before you can talk to a lawyer, and you don't need a lot of money, either. Many lawyers work on contingency, meaning they only get paid if you win. So, once you have a reasonable amount of information to support your concerns, reach out to someone who can help, ideally in your state, province, or area, who knows your local laws. You can find lawyers in the US on Hush Line's User Directory.</p>
<p>You don't have to show up perfectly to have a productive conversation, but when you speak to the legal professional (who can legally provide attorney-client confidentiality), make sure you sign a contract establishing that person as your legal representation.</p>
<p><em>Takeaway: It likely won't cost you anything to consult with a lawyer.</em></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="be-prepared-to-drop-it">Be Prepared To Drop It<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-blow-the-whistle-without-losing-your-career#be-prepared-to-drop-it" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Be Prepared To Drop It" title="Direct link to Be Prepared To Drop It">​</a></h2>
<p>Not everything concerning is illegal or unethical. If you learn that there's not a case to be made, be prepared to walk away. If you're going to risk your career, it should be for a slam dunk, not a reaching claim. And if you can't produce hard evidence, you may find lawyers hesitant to take your case.</p>
<p><em>Takeaway: It's better to live to fight another day.</em></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ready-now-resign">Ready? Now, Resign<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-blow-the-whistle-without-losing-your-career#ready-now-resign" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Ready? Now, Resign" title="Direct link to Ready? Now, Resign">​</a></h2>
<p>It may be a shock to hear, but if you have a strong case, you should immediately start looking for another job. "Difference in company vision" can be an adequate reason to give to your next employer for leaving your last role. Why resign? Once you're outted as someone behind a lawsuit targeting your company, everyone around you will now see you as a risk to their livelihoods. You've become a problem, and if the law keeps you in your job, it may be social ostracism and a dead-end career ladder that makes you finally leave.</p>
<p>The greater risk than simply being the office pariah is the stress that blowing the whistle can bring into your life. There are many stories of people spiraling into drug use, depression, and even suicide. Imagine having a career you've dreamed of your entire life taken from you because you wanted to do the right thing. Think it'll be easy to find a job after the fallout? Most whistleblowers change careers entirely because they're wearing the scarlet letter of Liability.</p>
<p>Many lawsuits can take years, and lawyers have methods of keeping you anonymous, at least through the most sensitive stages of the process. By the time your name comes out, you'll be in a different role at a different company, and will have more safeguards than you would from inside the organization you're in litigation against.</p>
<p><em>Takeaway: Fight from the outside to protect yourself and your career.</em></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="eh-lets-just-drop-it">Eh, Let's Just Drop It<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-blow-the-whistle-without-losing-your-career#eh-lets-just-drop-it" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Eh, Let's Just Drop It" title="Direct link to Eh, Let's Just Drop It">​</a></h2>
<p>It's never a bad decision to take time to assess whether you want to go through with the process of disclosure. If you have a family, valued career, a high-paying job, or something else keeping you at your job, you're going to feel a strong sense of protectionism to guard what's yours, and that's good.</p>
<p>If you decide to walk away from the issue you identified, AND you haven't raised any alarms internally - talking to coworkers, HR, legal, or using your computer to research the crimes you're investigating - you can safely go back to your normal life. And if you find yourself in a workplace with ethics you don't align with, it's okay to look for a new job, even if the company has a name that looks great on a resume.</p>
<p><em>Takeaway: Don't raise alarms, and you can make decisions without stress.</em></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Glenn Sorrentino</name>
            <uri>https://scidsg.org</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Hush Line" term="Hush Line"/>
        <category label="whistleblowing" term="whistleblowing"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hush Line's Sustainable Impact Model]]></title>
        <id>https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model</id>
        <link href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model"/>
        <updated>2025-03-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Impact Model Diagram]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Impact Model Diagram" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/cover-60ebdcf3bf80033c9bfc3ee1f8181a1d.png" width="2473" height="1932" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>[This article is a draft and subject to update.] It's tough out there. Grants seem harder and harder to come by, and the cost of maintaining software services is ongoing. We were honored to receive a grant from the Data Empowerment Fund for $100k; it enabled us to reach a stable, robust, production-ready state, enabling our first paying customers and many more free users. But another grant we were crossing our fingers for fell through, and it's a reminder that this cannot be our primary funding source for stable, long-term infrastructure.</p>
<p>This realization is not new - I understood the scarcity of funding compared to the for-profit world. It was a lesson learned quickly, and as someone with a career as a product designer, SaaS seemed like an obvious solution to a ubiquitous problem in my new industry. This is not only an obvious solution but also one with a significant monetary upside that, and combined with our 501(c)(3) structure, offers a compelling model for self-sustainability and community empowerment.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-consumer-non-profit-software-landscape">The Consumer Non-Profit Software Landscape<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#the-consumer-non-profit-software-landscape" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Consumer Non-Profit Software Landscape" title="Direct link to The Consumer Non-Profit Software Landscape">​</a></h2>
<p>If you work outside the tech or tech-adjacent industries, you'll be hard-pressed to name a single non-profit or open-source piece of software, let alone one you use. You'll probably be able to name a lot of consumer alternatives - Google, Apple, Dropbox, Outlook, Slack - though all of these use open-source software to drive their closed-source development, their model is to charge a lot, make it expensive to leave, and lock you into a system to which you become dependent.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-problem-with-for-profit-software">The Problem With For-Profit Software<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#the-problem-with-for-profit-software" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Problem With For-Profit Software" title="Direct link to The Problem With For-Profit Software">​</a></h3>
<p>The astronomical profits Big Tech companies make create new record levels of wealth inequality that allow Big Tech CEOs to <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/02/28/1232564250/billionaire-benioff-buys-hawaii-land-salesforce" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">displace communities and businesses for their private use</a>. At the same time, the dream of home ownership is a fading reality for most people.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Hawaii has long been a place where the world's elite has flocked. And tech billionaires are now among the newest cadre of migrants to buy land in the islands. Amazon founder Jeff Bezos owns a sprawling beach mansion in Maui. Facebook co-founder Mark Zuckerberg has plans to build a bunker on his land in Kauai, according to Wired. Benioff's former boss, Oracle co-founder Larry Ellison, owns 98% of Lanai. And the list goes on.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>What's different here is that rather than focusing on coastal mansions in gated communities, Benioff is buying property in a rural residential town. In the majority of instances, he's paid more than current market value, according to public records. For example, the longtime Mamane Bakery — known for its lilikoi cheesecake and mango-guava hot cross buns — shuttered after he purchased the land for more than 50% above the current market value.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="shifting-the-profit-model">Shifting The Profit Model<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#shifting-the-profit-model" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Shifting The Profit Model" title="Direct link to Shifting The Profit Model">​</a></h3>
<p>The most important part is that the upside for making money is so great that a successful application of it in the non-profit sector could create generational, self-funded charities that are legally required to do good. What if instead of buying for-profit, billionaire-making CRM software, you had an alternative whose profits went to reforming corruption in business? Instead of fighting for $100,000, what if an organization could organically make 100x that and give a large portion away?</p>
<p>This is our opportunity with Hush Line. Anonymous reporting is a cross-industry need, legally mandated in some sectors and countries. Open-source software is our development model, enabling community review of our source code and other organizations and individuals to use our software for free. Even though anyone can install our platform themselves, we understand that most people and organizations are non-technical and cannot operate and maintain their own software infrastructure. Additionally, if you're buying security software, it's imperative to know that the code treats your data the way the makers say it is.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="monetization--distribution-model">Monetization &amp; Distribution Model<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#monetization--distribution-model" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Monetization &amp; Distribution Model" title="Direct link to Monetization &amp; Distribution Model">​</a></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Hush Line Monetization Model" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/monetization-model-2f9ddf113ba6d13be4706a6f9e40d8a0.png" width="2473" height="1932" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="software">Software<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#software" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Software" title="Direct link to Software">​</a></h3>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="saas">SaaS<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#saas" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to SaaS" title="Direct link to SaaS">​</a></h4>
<p>If you visit <code>hushline.app</code> to create an account, you're using our software as a service (SaaS) platform. A free tier offers most people everything they need for a secure, anonymous tip line. We have a low-cost paid tier or licensed managed single-tenant instances for businesses or professionals who require more features. For developers, hobbyists, or businesses with technical proficiency, anyone can freely install and use all of Hush Line's features.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="paas">PaaS<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#paas" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to PaaS" title="Direct link to PaaS">​</a></h4>
<p>Some organizations may want their own independent app and infrastructure instead of using <code>hushline.app</code>. In this case, we offer managed single-tenant instances that are perfect for all sizes of business. We can rapidly deploy to the same infrastructure that the core Hush Line platform uses, or tailor any deployment to the needs of the organization. Costs are similar to ours, but end up being cheaper since only the main service uses a staging infrastructure.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Single Tenant Infrastructure" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/architecture-0b1bff9a6ccd928a20bc6c87c8019ba9.png" width="1604" height="1544" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="hardware">Hardware<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#hardware" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Hardware" title="Direct link to Hardware">​</a></h3>
<p>For high-risk tip line owners who do not want to trust any third-party services, we offer a hardware device that runs Hush Line locally as an Onion Service; higher security and anonymity are critical for their work for a smaller audience — human rights defenders, investigative journalists, or high-profile lawyers. We offer devices for $500 that are fully self-contained, Tor-only Hush Line instances. If your threat model is one in which you cannot trust any third-party infrastructure, this is your best option.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Personal Server" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/personal-server-4290b2a46b70ef477032aa2ecc8156d8.png" width="1024" height="455" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-opportunity">The Opportunity<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#the-opportunity" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Opportunity" title="Direct link to The Opportunity">​</a></h2>
<p>If successful, the market opportunity will be <a href="https://www.coherentmarketinsights.com/market-insight/whistleblowing-software-market-4595" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$238m in 2025, growing to over $300m in 2032</a>. Even on the very low end, becoming profitable is possible. It only takes about $3,000 to operate Hush Line's software annually. Once we surpass the point of platform financial stability, we will have money that will go toward more than making a few people rich.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whistleblower-fund">Whistleblower Fund<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#whistleblower-fund" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whistleblower Fund" title="Direct link to Whistleblower Fund">​</a></h2>
<p>As with any charitable cause, people are the point, and the folks we're helping are whistleblowers. These individuals often lose their careers and life savings and can suffer from significant mental health issues. To address this, we're starting a new whistleblower fund that will directly support whistleblowers' pragmatic needs, with a small portion reserved for the development and maintenance of the Hush Line platform.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="governance">Governance<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#governance" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Governance" title="Direct link to Governance">​</a></h3>
<p>Though the specifics are undecided at the moment, the fund may be a new independent non-profit, governed by former whistleblowers, whistleblower lawyers, and others.&nbsp;</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="funding-goals">Funding Goals<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#funding-goals" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Funding Goals" title="Direct link to Funding Goals">​</a></h3>
<p>If we chose a 70/30 distribution model, we would need recurring $1,000/mo donations, combined with sales, to "keep the lights on."</p>
<p>Ideally, we could afford ~10 hours/mo for an engineering contractor, around $2,000. To get to this amount, we'd need to raise or earn around $7,500/mo with the same 70/30 distribution for Hush Line to earn enough to cover everything needed. Eventually, as the fund grew in popularity, we could even sustain a full-time team.</p>
<p>In a perfect world, we can have a full team, which would require about 6-12 people, requiring $6,000,000 ARR (annual recurring revenue), giving Hush Line a $150,000 monthly budget, and providing $350,000 every month for direct whistleblower support!</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="financial-support-with-a-7030-distribution">Financial Support With a 70/30 Distribution<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#financial-support-with-a-7030-distribution" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Financial Support With a 70/30 Distribution" title="Direct link to Financial Support With a 70/30 Distribution">​</a></h4>
<table><thead><tr><th>Milestone</th><th>MRR</th><th>ARR</th><th>Monthly Hush Line Support</th><th>Monthly Whistlblower Support</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>💡 Keeping the lights on</td><td>$1,000</td><td>$12,000</td><td>$300</td><td>$700</td></tr><tr><td>❤️ 1 Contractor, Infra</td><td>$7,666</td><td>$92,000</td><td>$2,300</td><td>$5,367</td></tr><tr><td>🤩 Shangri La (6 Full-Time Employees, Infra)</td><td>$500,000</td><td>$6,000,000</td><td>$150,000</td><td>$350,000</td></tr></tbody></table>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="obstacles">Obstacles<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#obstacles" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Obstacles" title="Direct link to Obstacles">​</a></h2>
<p>While it seems straightforward, we face significant obstacles. The new organization governing the fund still needs to be formed. Will a 501(c)(3) be approved that explicitly supports whistleblowers? Federal staff have been laid off in record numbers, and the regulatory situation in the US government is tenuous at best.</p>
<p>Adoption is the largest barrier to success. While we don't need much, we're the new kid on the block, and as a non-profit with exactly $0 for advertising or sales as of writing this, it's a slow game. Large non-profits like Wikimedia, Signal, or Tor have a large and loyal donor-base. We're entering the industry during difficult economic and political times, and asking working people for their limited funds is a delicate thing.</p>
<p>There always seems to be more than one top priority when building software, but security is among the most important. Offering a centralized service makes you a target, and if we ever experience a data breach, it could cause significant reputational damage. Security is a moving target requiring constant vigilance and proactivity. Our engineering team is made up of security experts and industry leaders, but nothing is perfectly secure, and people are fallible.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-we-get-there">How We Get There<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/hushline-sustainable-model#how-we-get-there" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How We Get There" title="Direct link to How We Get There">​</a></h2>
<p>This year, we'll start the formation of the new fund and assemble a governing board that will ensure the funds are used as stated in our mission goals.</p>
<p>The individuals who oversee the fund will have a first-hand understanding of the battles people who speak up face: whistleblower lawyers, former whistleblowers, journalists, or others who support the needs of people engaging in responsible disclosure.</p>
<p>Do you know someone who should be on the Board? <a href="https://tips.hushline.app/to/glenn" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reach out to me on Hush Line</a>!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Glenn Sorrentino</name>
            <uri>https://scidsg.org</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Hush Line" term="Hush Line"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Should Never Use Work Devices To Disclose Information]]></title>
        <id>https://hushline.app/library/blog/dont-use-work-devices</id>
        <link href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/dont-use-work-devices"/>
        <updated>2025-03-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Impact Model Diagram]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Impact Model Diagram" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/tor-onion-62747a711df3c93bee6a06256b17eb05.png" width="1889" height="966" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Whistleblowing software adoption is on the rise. Legislation requiring companies to have internal and external methods of confidential reporting is active in the EU, and states in the US, including California, require companies to publicize the State's Attorney General's Office hotline phone number. At the same time, federal whistleblower protections are eroding at breakneck speed.</p>
<p>If you work at a larger organization, you've probably been asked to fill out "anonymous" surveys about team and company health, ways to improve, etc. Laughably, many times, these anonymous forms are actually logged-in Google Forms that are in no way anonymous.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dns-monitoring">DNS Monitoring<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/dont-use-work-devices#dns-monitoring" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to DNS Monitoring" title="Direct link to DNS Monitoring">​</a></h2>
<p>For remote workers, you're probably familiar with using VPNs to access work servers, email, or other internal-only things. VPNs for work allow you to operate as if you were in the office on an internal network. Here's an example from my home network's DNS logs:</p>
<table><thead><tr><th>Time</th><th>Type</th><th>Domain</th><th>Client</th><th>Status</th><th>Response</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>2025-03-16 12:18:17</td><td>A</td><td>tips.hushline.app</td><td>glenns-m3</td><td>OK (answered by localhost#5335)</td><td>IP (7.0ms)</td></tr><tr><td>2025-03-16 12:18:17</td><td>HTTPS</td><td>tips.hushline.app</td><td>glenns-m3</td><td>OK (answered by localhost#5335)</td><td>CNAME (141.5ms)</td></tr><tr><td>2025-03-16 12:18:17</td><td>A</td><td>hushline.app</td><td>glenns-m3.pivpn</td><td>OK (answered by localhost#5335)</td><td>CNAME (33.8ms)</td></tr><tr><td>2025-03-16 12:18:17</td><td>A</td><td>checkonline.home-assistant.io</td><td>192.168.0.166</td><td>OK (already forwarded)</td><td>N/A</td></tr><tr><td>2025-03-16 12:18:17</td><td>A</td><td>checkonline.home-assistant.io</td><td>192.168.0.166</td><td>OK (answered by localhost#5335)</td><td>IP (7.6ms)</td></tr><tr><td>2025-03-16 12:18:17</td><td>A</td><td>s1.openairinfo.com</td><td>192.168.0.117</td><td>OK (answered by localhost#5335)</td><td>IP (7.0ms)</td></tr><tr><td>2025-03-16 12:18:17</td><td>AAAA</td><td>s1.openairinfo.com</td><td>192.168.0.117</td><td>OK (cache)</td><td>NODATA (0.0ms)</td></tr><tr><td>2025-03-16 12:18:17</td><td>AAAA</td><td>s1.openairinfo.com</td><td>192.168.0.117</td><td>OK (cache)</td><td>NODATA (0.0ms)</td></tr></tbody></table>
<p>Since I've given my computer a custom hostname, instead of seeing an internal IP address, which&nbsp;could&nbsp;tell you a lot, I can easily find my computer with a human-readable name. Now, if someone runs a company and receives a report of serious allegations of wrongdoing, they can do one of a few things: 1. take the tip, act on it, and save lots of money, or, 2. find the person who submitted the report and "fix" the problem. Most of the time, companies choose option 2. If I access the network using a VPN, the logs are no different.</p>
<p>So, if on March 16th at around noon, a company receives a tip that threatens to go to the press if action isn't taken, all they need to do is look back through their network logs to see who visited the tip line then. "But the system is anonymous because I didn't have to log in to submit a message!" No, sorry. "But it's end-to-end encrypted!" That only means that only the intended recipient can read the message, but in this case, I don't need to know the contents of the message; I just need to know who sent it.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-dangers-of-mdm-and-edr-software">The Dangers of MDM and EDR Software<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/dont-use-work-devices#the-dangers-of-mdm-and-edr-software" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Dangers of MDM and EDR Software" title="Direct link to The Dangers of MDM and EDR Software">​</a></h2>
<p>Some employers ask employees to install MDM (mobile device management) software on their personal devices. DO NOT DO THIS! MDM software enables monitoring of the contents of your phone, including the ability to add or remove apps, check your contacts, monitor your location, view browsing history and network connections, and see a full list of the applications you have installed. It's basically an administrator account run by your company. Does&nbsp;any&nbsp;app your company offers have a custom keyboard? These can log your keystrokes, so switch back to a system keyboard if possible. If your company uses EDR (endpoint detection and response) software, it can log keystrokes for forensic analysis, including texts sent over any application, including Signal.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-do-instead">What to do Instead?<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/dont-use-work-devices#what-to-do-instead" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What to do Instead?" title="Direct link to What to do Instead?">​</a></h2>
<p>It's best to use a personal device on a private network or that you own, including your phone. Again, no corporate MDM or EDR software should be present on your device. One way to check if anything is installed currently is to check for "Profiles" in your phone's settings. Nothing from your company or anything else you don't recognize should be there.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="low-threat-scenarios">Low Threat Scenarios<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/dont-use-work-devices#low-threat-scenarios" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Low Threat Scenarios" title="Direct link to Low Threat Scenarios">​</a></h3>
<p>In most situations, people want to report non-sensitive information. Using your personal device on a non-work network is perfect for this scenario. App owners could add IP address logging, but in this case, your IP will only show general location information. If that IP address becomes caught up in illegal activity elsewhere, law enforcement could subpoena the issuing ISP for customer information.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="medium-to-high-threat-scenarios">Medium to High Threat Scenarios<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/dont-use-work-devices#medium-to-high-threat-scenarios" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Medium to High Threat Scenarios" title="Direct link to Medium to High Threat Scenarios">​</a></h3>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="non-onion-services">Non-Onion Services<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/dont-use-work-devices#non-onion-services" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Non-Onion Services" title="Direct link to Non-Onion Services">​</a></h4>
<p>When someone does have reason to worry about using a tip line, including when disclosing serious issues of governmental corruption, national security, or other ethical or legal concerns, they may use our native Onion services. Using Tor Browser with an Onion service enables the highest levels of protection, because connections never leave the Tor Anonymizing Network.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Tor Regular Connections" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/tor-regular-8f67c68cc6180255aafc61c480809bad.png" width="2586" height="1066" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="onion-connections">Onion Connections<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/dont-use-work-devices#onion-connections" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Onion Connections" title="Direct link to Onion Connections">​</a></h4>
<p>When you connect to a normal website on Tor Browser, it uses a volunteer computer to exit the network and connect to that website. Theoretically, the exit computer could be compromised, and the originating requester could be deanonymized. This isn't possible using a .onion address because there is no exit connecting to the normal internet.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Tor Regular Connections" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/tor-onion-62747a711df3c93bee6a06256b17eb05.png" width="1889" height="966" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Glenn Sorrentino</name>
            <uri>https://scidsg.org</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Hush Line" term="Hush Line"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Newsrooms and Journalists Use Hush Line]]></title>
        <id>https://hushline.app/library/blog/newsrooms-and-journalists</id>
        <link href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/newsrooms-and-journalists"/>
        <updated>2025-03-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Encryption settings wireframe]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Encryption settings wireframe" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/cover-83ebca78119ff8ea946e2149fb19954e.png" width="1186" height="464" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Hush Line is a general-purpose anonymous reporting tool that can be used across a range of industries. In this article, we'll explore how journalists and newsrooms can quickly get started with a Hush Line account that'll enable anyone with an internet connection to reach you without downloading a new app or creating an account.</p>
<p>I've been working on private messengers for a while. In 2016, I worked on Signal's first desktop app redesign. Around the same time, I started working on OnionShare. This peer-to-peer file transfer tool uses the Tor Network to create ephemeral anonymous connections for leaking sources to journalists. The work led me to contribute to CalyxOS, a de-Googled Android OS, for a few years and eventually join the Board of Advisors for Distributed Denial of Secrets. This non-profit publishes and archives public interest hacked and leaked documents.</p>
<p>I love usability. My career has been as a product designer and user researcher for a Big Tech enterprise organization, where I worked on many exciting projects, including search, identity and authentication, voice, and more. But my passion for public interest work outweighed enterprise software, and I left to start Science &amp; Design and then create our first product, Hush Line.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-hush-line">What is Hush Line?<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/newsrooms-and-journalists#what-is-hush-line" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is Hush Line?" title="Direct link to What is Hush Line?">​</a></h2>
<p>Hush Line is a SaaS (software as a service) platform where anyone who needs a tip line can easily sign up for free. We already have journalists from ABC News, Mother Jones, Reveal, BBC, and more, and the service enables anyone in the public to reach them anonymously. Communications are end-to-end encrypted, and whistleblowers do not need to create an account or download any apps, including Tor Browser, in order to send a secure and private message that only the tip line owner can read.</p>
<p>We're different from other tools familiar to journalists, including SecureDrop and GlobaLeaks, because these options are self-hosted, meaning you need to run your own software or hardware infrastructure to use them. Conversely, Hush Line enables anyone to sign up for an account on a centralized service, eliminating the need for self-hosting. We're also free. Other solutions mean paying developers, buying specialized hardware, training staff, and following prescriptive workflows.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-to-use-hush-line">How to Use Hush Line<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/newsrooms-and-journalists#how-to-use-hush-line" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How to Use Hush Line" title="Direct link to How to Use Hush Line">​</a></h2>
<p>After signing up, you only need to add an encryption key to start receiving messages. If you use Proton Mail, it's as simple as entering your Proton address, and we'll import your public key into Hush Line! Now, when you receive rich notifications back to that same email address, your tips will seamlessly and automatically be decrypted in your inbox!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Encryption Settings" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/encryption-4b4eeea2385697c461c9519581e06ebb.png" width="2648" height="1844" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="add-information-about-yourself">Add Information About Yourself<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/newsrooms-and-journalists#add-information-about-yourself" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Add Information About Yourself" title="Direct link to Add Information About Yourself">​</a></h3>
<p>Include a descriptive bio and additional links in your profile details that point to your profiles on your newsroom websites, personal social media accounts, Signal username, or anything else that'll act as social proofs to help your community confirm authenticity.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Profile Settings" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/settings-52bca3e9975b743f52a009d2684272fd.png" width="2648" height="1844" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="self-authenticating-urls">Self-Authenticating URLs<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/newsrooms-and-journalists#self-authenticating-urls" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Self-Authenticating URLs" title="Direct link to Self-Authenticating URLs">​</a></h4>
<p>Adding a self-authenticating or verified URL is easy and helps us fast-track your account verification process. Just add a link to your Hush Line profile on your website, and include&nbsp;rel="me"&nbsp;in the anchor tag. Then, add your website to your profile details on Hush Line, and you'll see a checkmark appear.&nbsp;<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-verify-an-address-on-hush-line" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Here's a full tutorial on adding verified URLs</a>.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="request-account-verification">Request Account Verification<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/newsrooms-and-journalists#request-account-verification" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Request Account Verification" title="Direct link to Request Account Verification">​</a></h3>
<p>We offer free verified accounts to journalists and newsrooms. Once your account is ready, send a message to the <a href="https://tips.hushline.app/to/admin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hush Line Admin account</a>, including your Hush Line profile and a way to contact you if it's not already in your profile details.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="publicize-your-address">Publicize Your Address<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/newsrooms-and-journalists#publicize-your-address" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Publicize Your Address" title="Direct link to Publicize Your Address">​</a></h2>
<p>In order for people to know they can send you messages on Hush Line, they have to know you use it! The easiest and best way to share your tip line to ensure plausible deniability for sources is to share widely. Add a link to your Hush Line profile on your social media accounts, in your email signature, on your personal and professional websites, or anywhere else someone might go to attempt to contact you.</p>
<p>We already have received reports that users have received helpful messages from places with censored internet access.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="add-to-your-social-profile">Add to Your Social Profile<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/newsrooms-and-journalists#add-to-your-social-profile" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Add to Your Social Profile" title="Direct link to Add to Your Social Profile">​</a></h3>
<p>Fun fact: I started contributing to OnionShare because I found Micah Lee's Signal contact on his Twitter bio and reached out, and we've continued collaborating on it for years. With Hush Line, the person sending a message doesn't need to be a user of the platform or download an app, as in the case with Signal.</p>
<p><a href="https://tips.hushline.app/to/Paige_St_John" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Paige St. John</a>, a Pulitzer-awarded investigative journalist at the Los Angeles Times, adds a link to her Hush Line account on her LinkedIn profile:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Paige St. John" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/paige-fa39ce194e5bf8343bd6401fd98fec40.png" width="1353" height="1387" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><a href="https://tips.hushline.app/to/phocks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Joshua Byrd</a>, a journalist at ABC News, adds a link to his Hush Line account on his Mastodon profile:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Joshua Byrd" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/josh-3851f8f4a6e80eb19d9dcdd82eb3e53f.png" width="1368" height="1698" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="add-yourself-to-the-user-directory">Add Yourself to the User Directory<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/newsrooms-and-journalists#add-yourself-to-the-user-directory" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Add Yourself to the User Directory" title="Direct link to Add Yourself to the User Directory">​</a></h3>
<p>If someone comes to the Hush Line User Directory looking for someone who can help make your profile discoverable, there can be a difference between success and failure for them. Just toggle the option in your Profile settings, and you'll be listed where visitors can find you.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Directory Settings" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/settings-directory-575b92fa5913209ba6ab1729a1997149.png" width="2648" height="1844" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p><a href="https://tips.hushline.app/to/danielschulman" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Daniel Schulman</a>, deputy editor for news and politics at Mother Jones and the Center for Investigative Reporting, has opted into the directory so anyone can send him an anonymous, end-to-end encrypted message!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Daniel listing" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/directory-listing-73ac2eaa5fd590f648f3eeed0eb2eee3.png" width="1245" height="611" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/newsrooms-and-journalists#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Setting up Hush Line is so easy you'll wonder why you haven't done it sooner. If you need assistance, you can contact us on Hush Line at&nbsp;<a href="https://tips.hushline.app/to/admin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://tips.hushline.app/to/admin</a>!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Glenn Sorrentino</name>
            <uri>https://scidsg.org</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Hush Line" term="Hush Line"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Verify an Address on Hush Line]]></title>
        <id>https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-verify-an-address-on-hush-line</id>
        <link href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-verify-an-address-on-hush-line"/>
        <updated>2025-02-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Encryption settings wireframe]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Encryption settings wireframe" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/cover-ac8e73285f601f2dd19f2aa972fc0ad5.png" width="1917" height="940" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>One of Hush Line's strengths is offering free Verified badges to tip line owners who want to prevent phishing attacks by adding an additional measure of authenticity to their accounts...</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-1-link-to-your-hush-line-account">Step 1: Link To Your Hush Line Account<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-verify-an-address-on-hush-line#step-1-link-to-your-hush-line-account" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 1: Link To Your Hush Line Account" title="Direct link to Step 1: Link To Your Hush Line Account">​</a></h2>
<p>On a website that you own, or if you're a legal representative of a business on a site you have control of, add a link to your Hush Line profile. It can be located anywhere, but must include <code>rel="me"</code> in the link. For example:</p>
<div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar" style="color:#393A34;background-color:#f6f8fa"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">&lt;a href="https://tips.hushline.app/to/myaccount" rel="me"&gt;Message me on Hush Line&lt;/a&gt;</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>Note that your link doesn't have to say <code>Message me on Hush Line</code>, it just must contain <code>rel="me"</code> and point to your profile.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-2-update-your-bio">Step 2: Update Your Bio<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-verify-an-address-on-hush-line#step-2-update-your-bio" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 2: Update Your Bio" title="Direct link to Step 2: Update Your Bio">​</a></h2>
<p>In your Hush Line settings, from the <code>Profile</code> tab, scroll to find <code>Profile Details</code>. You'll see four fields in which you can add any information that helps your community trust that your profile belongs to you. One of those fields should be to the website whose link you just added to your Hush Line address.</p>
<p>When you click <code>Update Bio</code> we will automatically verify that the code from Step 1 exists, and you'll see a new checkmark!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Verified URL wireframe" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/verified-url-83a01aad6936f85168f297bd3b3e1363.png" width="1150" height="876" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-3-check-your-profile">Step 3: Check Your Profile<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/how-to-verify-an-address-on-hush-line#step-3-check-your-profile" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 3: Check Your Profile" title="Direct link to Step 3: Check Your Profile">​</a></h2>
<p>Once you verify a URL, anyone who visits your profile will see a checkmark, demonstrating that you own or control the listed website.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Verified URL wireframe of profile" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/verified-url-profile-28a568cdcf2eb346d96669a826e81c0a.png" width="1150" height="882" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>🎉 Congratulations! You now have a verified URL on your Hush Line Profile!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Glenn Sorrentino</name>
            <uri>https://scidsg.org</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Hush Line" term="Hush Line"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why A Signal Tip Line Isn't Enough]]></title>
        <id>https://hushline.app/library/blog/why-a-signal-tip-line-isnt-enough</id>
        <link href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/why-a-signal-tip-line-isnt-enough"/>
        <updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Encryption settings wireframe]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Encryption settings wireframe" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/cover-45d39fa572b924dfb0d5ac8ba038a159.png" width="3834" height="1880" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>I love Signal. I was almost their first full-time designer when the team was only four people with a physical office back in the Mission in San Francisco. I turned the offer down because I was too junior in my career to feel like I could be as effective as I knew I could be with more time at the Big Tech company I worked for...</p>
<p>...I volunteered, rejecting even being paid for my time since I had a job that paid enough. And I personally use Signal almost exclusively, so there’s no shade when I say emphatically (especially looking at you, journalists), “Signal is not enough!” Below, we’ll look at internet and messaging usage data in the United States to inform a data-informed tip line strategy.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-data">The Data<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/why-a-signal-tip-line-isnt-enough#the-data" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Data" title="Direct link to The Data">​</a></h2>
<p>There’s a particular bias against anything but Signal if you’re a journalist in the US, but this bias seriously hurts your potential impact. When I worked with the team, adoption was one of the biggest problems to solve as they were hovering around 100K users, even with the stamp of approval from Snowden. Now, the app has had a nearly 700x increase in users at around 70M globally! It’s excellent news for the team at Signal — a foundation was created (just for Signal), a billionaire is their chairman, and their future is all but guaranteed.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Encryption settings wireframe" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/signal-users-99a2078a3cc2a3d44a70bcc8eeaf17d4.webp" width="1530" height="750" class="img_ev3q">
Signal Users Globally from 2019–2024
However the total number of internet users in 2025 is ~5.5B worldwide, and Signal is but ~1.3% of that total share.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Encryption settings wireframe" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/internet-users-27aa2f089a393cef17ddb978a395f37b.png" width="1456" height="962" class="img_ev3q">
Total Internet and Social Users in 2025
Okay, so Signal might have a modest share of the total pie, but people in the US must get it, right? Looking at the top messaging apps, it doesn’t seem so. In fact, Signal isn’t in the top 10.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Encryption settings wireframe" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/phone-usage-ce9c916c300213456dc98d22f3c12189.png" width="1446" height="1220" class="img_ev3q">
Top Messaging Apps in the United States
Here’s a personal story that I think about all the time. When I was working with the team, Moxie traveled down to Menlo Park to personally work with the WhatsApp team to integrate the Signal Protocol. It was a normal, slow morning when he said that it was done and deployed, almost as an “oh, by the way,” kind of thing, and it was at that moment, my mind exploded. Just like that, 1,000,000,000 (one billion) WhatsApp users worldwide had the strongest encryption on the market. Now, it’s used by two of the top four most-used messaging apps in the world, so by all counts, the scale of their positive impact deserves a Nobel Prize, in my opinion. Having said that, Signal itself isn’t among the top 10 most used apps in the United States.
A more recent story: I was visiting one of my besties, whose son I’m the godfather of, who is now 19 years old and studying cybersecurity. Since my career has been in software, and most recently in the security and privacy space, I was eager to introduce him to influential people I know and to try to give him real-world experience, maybe with work on Hush Line. “If I’m going to intro you to ppl, let’s move to Signal” I said. “What’s Signal?” was the reply to which I had to put my phone down and take a breath before replying, “Oh, young one…”</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="your-tip-line-strategy">Your Tip Line Strategy<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/why-a-signal-tip-line-isnt-enough#your-tip-line-strategy" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Your Tip Line Strategy" title="Direct link to Your Tip Line Strategy">​</a></h2>
<p>Should you abandon Signal? Absolutely not. But it can’t be your only solution for people to reach you. Other solutions like Proton Mail have emerged as great, lower-friction options, but as of 2023, even they only have 100M users, less than 2% of all internet users.
On the other hand, email is used by ~4.5B users worldwide. But what’s better than ~4.5B users? What about everyone? Now, let’s talk about Hush Line.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Encryption settings wireframe" src="https://hushline.app/library/assets/images/submit-message-2c17c1d23f788340668ce0cb3ae61fb6.png" width="1213" height="994" class="img_ev3q">
Anyone internet user can send a message
Hush Line is our anonymous reporting platform that doesn’t require internet users to create an account or download any apps to use. Tip Line owners can have messages forwarded to their email service of choice, and messages are end-to-end encrypted. Someone submitting a message with an elevated threat model can use our Onion Service to access Hush Line anonymously using Tor Browser.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="get-going">Get Going<a href="https://hushline.app/library/blog/why-a-signal-tip-line-isnt-enough#get-going" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Get Going" title="Direct link to Get Going">​</a></h2>
<p>The best news? We’re free, open-source, and non-profit managed. Our team has worked on the most ubiquitous secure messaging platforms in the world, and we deeply care about making it easy for whistleblowers to find help. Are you making it harder than it needs to be for vulnerable people who need help? If you’re only using Signal, the answer is yes.
Sign up for Hush Line at <a href="https://tips.hushline.app/register" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://tips.hushline.app/register</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Glenn Sorrentino</name>
            <uri>https://scidsg.org</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Hush Line" term="Hush Line"/>
        <category label="Signal" term="Signal"/>
    </entry>
</feed>